<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roadmap on Apache Camel</title>
    <link>https://camel.apache.org/categories/Roadmap/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Roadmap on Apache Camel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://camel.apache.org/categories/Roadmap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Camel Kafka Connector: Introducing the latest project in the ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/Camel-Kafka-connector-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/Camel-Kafka-connector-intro/</guid>
      <description>The Apache Camel community introduces a new subproject in the ecosystem: Camel-Kafka-Connector. This project born as a PoC exploring the possibility of leveraging the Apache Camel components as Kafka source and sink connectors. The main idea behind the project is reusing the Camel Components&amp;rsquo; flexibility in a simple way, through a configuration file mixing Kafka Connect configuration and Camel route definitions and options.
What is Kafka Connect? It is an Apache Kafka&amp;rsquo;s framework that defines a standardized way to stream data in and out a kafka broker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Camel 3 is only 2 months away</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/Camel3-2monthsaway/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/Camel3-2monthsaway/</guid>
      <description>The Camel team is busy working on the last set of work for Apache Camel 3. Today the 2nd release candidate was built and published on a staging repository for early adopters to give it a try.
As I am busy myself then I just wanted to write a short blog post to keep the community posted that Apache Camel 3 is on the way, and that we expect it to be released by end of this year (sometime in November or December).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>