<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Apache Camel</title>
    <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Apache Camel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://camel.apache.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Camel 2020 Release Schedule</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/LTS-Release-Schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/LTS-Release-Schedule/</guid>
      <description>The Apache Camel project is moving to release schedule with Long Term Support (LTS) and non-LTS releases.
The plan is to have 2 yearly LTS releases and then non-LTS releases in between.
This allows the Camel project to innovate and move much faster in non-LTS releases.
And as well to offer production stable branches (LTS) where end users can stay on for a longer period of time and get CVEs and important/critical bug fixes only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RELEASE 3.1.0</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-3-1-0.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-3-1-0.html</guid>
      <description>The Camel community announces the immediate availability of Camel 3.1.0, a new minor release with over 291 new features, improvements and fixes.
All users of Camel 3.0 are encouraged to upgrade to Camel 3.1 soon because there are some major memory usage optimizations in this release. We also plan to retire Camel 3.0 very soon due to this. Please read our Camel 3.x upgrade guide that describes how to upgrade Camel 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Summer of Code 2020 announced</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/GSoC-2020-announced/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/GSoC-2020-announced/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago Google Summer of Code announced that Apache Software Foundation is again elected to participate as a mentor organization.
We are looking for ideas, students and mentors willing to participate in GSoC 2020. Anyone in the Camel community can propose an idea, look at the JIRA issues labeled gsoc2020 or create new issues with ideas and set the gsoc2020 label. Have a look at the Mentor guide to understand the role of the mentor and the obligations you would take on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFP for ApacheCon North America 2020</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/ApacheConNA-2020-CFP/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/ApacheConNA-2020-CFP/</guid>
      <description>As previous year Apache Camel is part of ApacheCon 2020 in North America. This year the conference will be held at the Sheraton, in New Orleans, September 28th through October 2nd, 2020.
The call for presentations for ApacheCon North America 2020 is now open and the wider Camel community members are encouraged to submit. Look for the Camel/Integration track when submitting.
We&amp;rsquo;re most interested to see talks that offer learning experience to the attendees, so talks that present new parts of the Camel ecosystem (Camel K, Camel Quarkus, Camel Kafka Connector), talks showing off lessons learned, use cases, and visions on where software integration is heading in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RELEASE 2.25.0</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-2-25-0.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-2-25-0.html</guid>
      <description>The Camel community announces the immediate availability of Camel 2.25.0, a new minor release with 112 improvements and fixes.
Please note that Camel 2.25.x is the last minor release for Camel 2.
The artifacts are published and ready for you to download from the Central Maven repository. For more details please take a look at the resolved issues.
Many thanks to all who made this release possible.
On behalf of the Camel PMC,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RELEASE 3.0.1</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-3-0-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-3-0-1.html</guid>
      <description>The Camel community announces the immediate availability of Camel 3.0.1, the first patch release for the 3.0.x branch with 41 improvements and fixes.
The artifacts are published and ready for you to download from the Central Maven repository. For more details please take a look at the resolved issues.
Many thanks to all who made this release possible.
On behalf of the Camel PMC,
Gregor Zurowski</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camel at FOSDEM 2020</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/FOSDEM-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 13:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/FOSDEM-2020/</guid>
      <description>What FOSDEM is free as in beer grassroots event for free software/open source communities to meet, share ideas and collaborate. You&amp;rsquo;ll find over 800 talks spread over 35 rooms of Université libre de Bruxelles campus over the first weekend of February. And building on last year&amp;rsquo;s well-received BoF session Camel is returning to FOSDEM.
When FOSDEM 2020 is on 1st (from 9:30 to 19:00) and 2nd (from 9:00 to 18:00) of February.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Web API Component</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/CustomWebApiComponent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/CustomWebApiComponent/</guid>
      <description>Have you built a new great Web API for your product? Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be wonderful to have it available as a part of the great Apache Camel component family? We would love it.
The community just released Camel 3 which is more modular, lightweight and already includes lots of components (300+) to quickly integrate various systems consuming or producing data. All of these components can be used with the same integration domain specific language (DSL) based on the famous Enterprise Integration Patterns (EIPs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CAPI Gateway: Using Apache Camel at the European Commission</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/capi-gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/capi-gateway/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working at the European Commission for the last 4 years as a Software Architect, working for a unit responsible for developing reusable components, and advocating open source software. In this context, we organized already a couple of Hackathons and Bug bounties open to all the open source communities.
In the team, we worked already a couple of times with Apache Camel, and I like the elegance and performance compared with other integration frameworks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camel 2019 in Numbers</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/2019-Numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/2019-Numbers/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s the time of the year where we take a look back at 2019, and compile a brief summary of the Apache Camel project.
The big news of 2019 was the much anticipated release of Apache Camel 3.
Family of projects It was also in 2019 that the Camel project became a faimily of projects by introducing:
 Camel K Camel Quarkus  Making Apache Camel a trilogy. But it does not stop there; in early 2020 three will become five when we release:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RELEASE 2.24.3</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-2-24-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-2-24-3.html</guid>
      <description>The Camel community announces the immediate availability of the new patch release Camel 2.24.3. This release contains 25 fixes and improvements applied in the past weeks by the community on the camel-2.24.x branch. It is the last planned patched release for the camel-2.24.x branch.
The artifacts are published and ready for you to download either from the Apache mirrors or from the Central Maven repository. For more details please take a look at the resolved issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JBoss Asylum Podcast about Apache Camel 3</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/Podcast47/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/Podcast47/</guid>
      <description>JBoss Asylm Podcast episode 47: What do you call an Apache Camel with 3 humps
Claus Ibsen and Luca Burgazzoli sits down with Emanual and Max (hosts) and talks about what is coming in Apache Camel 3 on topics like Camel K and Camel Quarkus. We also cover Camel&amp;rsquo;s place in the modern world with cloud native and serverless workloads. And at the end we have some bits about what&amp;rsquo;s coming next in Camel 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language Support for Apache Camel - VS Code extension 0.0.20</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/LanguageSupportTooling-0.0.20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/LanguageSupportTooling-0.0.20/</guid>
      <description>During the past months, several noticeable new features have been added to improve the developer experience of application based on Apache Camel. These updates are available in the 0.0.20 release of Visual Studio (VS) Code extension.
Before going into the list of updates in detail, I want to note that I mentioned in the title the VS Code Extension release because VS Code extension is covering the broader set of new features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Camel Kafka Connector: Introducing the latest project in the ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/Camel-Kafka-connector-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/Camel-Kafka-connector-intro/</guid>
      <description>The Apache Camel community introduces a new subproject in the ecosystem: Camel-Kafka-Connector. This project born as a PoC exploring the possibility of leveraging the Apache Camel components as Kafka source and sink connectors. The main idea behind the project is reusing the Camel Components&amp;rsquo; flexibility in a simple way, through a configuration file mixing Kafka Connect configuration and Camel route definitions and options.
What is Kafka Connect? It is an Apache Kafka&amp;rsquo;s framework that defines a standardized way to stream data in and out a kafka broker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Camel 3 What&#39;s New (top 10)</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/Camel3-Whatsnew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/Camel3-Whatsnew/</guid>
      <description>Apache Camel 3 was released last thursday November 28th 2019, which also happens to be the day of the US Thanksgiving. This was not intentionally but we can say its a big thanks from us to the community with a brand new major version of Camel - this does not come often by. In fact its 10 years since Camel 2 hit the streets. So this 3rd generation is long overdue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RELEASE 3.0.0</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-3-0-0.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-3-0-0.html</guid>
      <description>The Camel community announces the immediate availability of Camel 3.0.0, a new major release with over 1000 new features, improvements and fixes.
Please read our migration guide the describes how to upgrade Camel 2.x applications to Camel 3.0.
The artifacts are published and ready for you to download from the Central Maven repository. For more details please take a look at the resolved issues.
Many thanks to all who made this release possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Camel on top-5 in the ASF annual 2019 report</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/ASF-Report-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/ASF-Report-2019/</guid>
      <description>The ASF Annual 2019 Report includes 25 highlights where Apache Camel is referred twice as a top-5 project:
 10. Top 5 Apache repositories by number of commits: Camel, Hadoop, HBase, Beam, and Flink; 20. GitHub traffic: Top 5 most active Apache sources &amp;ndash;visits: Spark, Camel, Flink, Kafka, and Airflow;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RELEASE 3.0.0-RC3</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-3-0-0-RC3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-3-0-0-RC3.html</guid>
      <description>The Camel community announces the immediate availability of Camel 3.0.0-RC3, the third release candidate towards a new 3.0.0 major release with 48 improvements and fixes.
The artifacts are published and ready for you to download from the Central Maven repository. For more details please take a look at the resolved issues.
Many thanks to all who made this release possible.
On behalf of the Camel PMC,
Gregor Zurowski</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camel K on CNCF Serverless Landscape</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/CamelK-CNCF-Landscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/CamelK-CNCF-Landscape/</guid>
      <description>The Apache Camel K project is now listed on the CNCF (Cloud Native Computing Foundation) interactive landscape; which lists all known open source projects that works with kubernetes and cloud platforms.
  Camel K CNCF landscape (Click to enlarge)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RELEASE 3.0.0-RC2</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-3-0-0-RC2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-3-0-0-RC2.html</guid>
      <description>The Camel community announces the immediate availability of Camel 3.0.0-RC2, the second release candidate towards a new 3.0.0 major release with 94 improvements and fixes.
The artifacts are published and ready for you to download from the Central Maven repository. For more details please take a look at the resolved issues.
Many thanks to all who made this release possible.
On behalf of the Camel PMC,
Gregor Zurowski</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Camel 3 is only 2 months away</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/Camel3-2monthsaway/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/Camel3-2monthsaway/</guid>
      <description>The Camel team is busy working on the last set of work for Apache Camel 3. Today the 2nd release candidate was built and published on a staging repository for early adopters to give it a try.
As I am busy myself then I just wanted to write a short blog post to keep the community posted that Apache Camel 3 is on the way, and that we expect it to be released by end of this year (sometime in November or December).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RELEASE 2.23.4</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-2-23-4.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-2-23-4.html</guid>
      <description>The Camel community announces the immediate availability of the new patch release Camel 2.23.4, the last planned patch release for the camel-2.23.x branch. This release contains 18 fixes and improvements applied in the past weeks by the community on the camel-2.23.x branch.
The artifacts are published and ready for you to download either from the Apache mirrors or from the Central Maven repository. For more details please take a look at the resolved issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RELEASE 2.24.2</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-2-24-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-2-24-2.html</guid>
      <description>The Camel community announces the immediate availability of the new patch release Camel 2.24.2. This release contains 20 fixes and improvements applied in the past weeks by the community on the camel-2.24.x branch.
The artifacts are published and ready for you to download either from the Apache mirrors or from the Central Maven repository. For more details please take a look at the resolved issues.
Many thanks to all who made this release possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camel at ApacheCon North America 2019</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/ApacheConNA-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 16:45:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/ApacheConNA-2019/</guid>
      <description>Apache Camel is part of ApacheCon 2019 in North America this year celebrating the 20th year anniversary of Apache Software Foundation.
On the Integration track you will find out all about the state of Apache Camel from Claus Ibsen, Sami Adranly will present Camel based data integration platform at Uber called Medley Nicola Ferraro and Andrea Tarocchi will be talking about Camel K and Camel K with Knative, Bob Paulin will make the cloud integration friendly in Configuring Apache Camel for the Cloud and Michael Costello will talk about serverless integration with Camel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RELEASE 3.0.0-RC1</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-3-0-0-RC1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-3-0-0-RC1.html</guid>
      <description>The Camel community announces the immediate availability of Camel 3.0.0-RC1, the first release candidate towards a new 3.0.0 major release with 148 improvements and fixes.
The artifacts are published and ready for you to download from the Central Maven repository. For more details please take a look at the resolved issues.
Many thanks to all who made this release possible.
On behalf of the Camel PMC,
Gregor Zurowski</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RELEASE 2.24.0</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-2-24-0.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/release-2-24-0.html</guid>
      <description>The Camel community announces the immediate availability of the new minor release Camel 2.24.0. This release contains 156 fixes and improvements. An overview of the changes is available here.
The artifacts are published and ready for you to download either from the Apache mirrors or from the Central Maven repository. For more details please take a look at the resolved issues.
Many thanks to all who made this release possible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>