<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Communities on Apache Camel</title><link>https://camel.apache.org/community/</link><description>Recent content in Communities on Apache Camel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://camel.apache.org/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Articles</title><link>https://camel.apache.org/community/articles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://camel.apache.org/community/articles/</guid><description>Camel Videos Camel Riders in the Cloud - A 30 minute video from March 2018 where Claus presents using Camel with microservices and containers as cloud native applications, and the best practices around this. Agile Integration with Apache Camel microservices in containers on Kubernetes - A 45 minute video from fall 2017 where Claus presents at CodeEurope in Poland. Containerised Integration with Apache Camel - A 70 minute video from August 2017 where Claus Ibsen present how developers can get started with Kubernetes/OpenShift on a local cluster and build and run Camel microservices in the cluster.</description></item><item><title>Books</title><link>https://camel.apache.org/community/books/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://camel.apache.org/community/books/</guid><description>This page lists the known books about Apache Camel. If you happen to know a book which is not listed then please contact us, for example using the Mailing Lists.
Camel in Action 2nd edition Camel in Action Apache Camel Developer&amp;rsquo;s Cookbook Camel Design Patterns Mastering Apache Camel Apache Camel Essentials Instant Apache Camel Message Routing Instant Apache Camel Messaging System Enterprise Integration Patterns Camel in Action 2nd edition Camel in Action 2nd edition by Claus Ibsen and Jonathan Anstey.</description></item><item><title>Camel Extra components</title><link>https://camel.apache.org/community/camel-extra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://camel.apache.org/community/camel-extra/</guid><description>Camel Extra project contains a number of extension components which due to GPL/LGPL licensing cannot be hosted at Apache.</description></item><item><title>Sources</title><link>https://camel.apache.org/community/sources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://camel.apache.org/community/sources/</guid><description>## Web Browsing of git
To browse via the web:
https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf/camel.git ## Web Browing Using FishEye
A hearty thanks to Atlassian for providing FishEye hosting for Camel. Below is the URL to browse the Subversion repo via FishEye:
https://fisheye6.atlassian.com/browse/camel-git ## Checking out from git
git clone https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf/camel.git Only project developers can commit to the git via this method. SSH must be installed on your client machine. Enter your site password when prompted.</description></item><item><title>Support</title><link>https://camel.apache.org/community/irc-room/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://camel.apache.org/community/irc-room/</guid><description>## IRC
You can hang out on IRC in the #apache-camel room at freenode with other Apache Camel developers and users.
Using an IRC client Here are the connection details.
server port room irc.freenode.net 6667 #apache-camel Gitter Room Apache Camel is also on Gitter in the apache/apache-camel room which you can access from a web browser.</description></item><item><title>Support</title><link>https://camel.apache.org/community/mailing-list/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://camel.apache.org/community/mailing-list/</guid><description>## Mailing Lists
Use Camel User List
You should post and subscriber to the Camel User List for all your questions on using Camel, or how to do X with Camel etc. If in doubt use this list. The other list Camel Developer List, is for the Camel team to discus development of the actual Camel project; do not use this list for question on using Camel. Again to re-iterate, use the Camel User List, for you Camel questions.</description></item><item><title>Support</title><link>https://camel.apache.org/community/support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://camel.apache.org/community/support/</guid><description>Getting help If you are experiencing problems using Camel then please report your problem to our mailing list. This allows the entire community to help with your problem. If indeed a bug has been identified in the Camel software, then document the problem in our Issue Tracker. Please refrain from immediately opening a ticket in the issue tracker unless you are certain it&amp;rsquo;s a problem in the Camel software.</description></item><item><title>Team</title><link>https://camel.apache.org/community/team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://camel.apache.org/community/team/</guid><description>This page lists who we are. By all means add yourself to the list - lets sort it in alphabetical order
Committers When posting to the mailing lists, use plain text mails. Do not use HTML mails. HTML mails is more likely to be targeted as spam mails and will be rejected; as well it&amp;rsquo;s not easily readable by others.
Name ID Organisation Aaron Mulder ammulder Chariot Solutions Akitoshi Yoshida ay SAP Andrea Cosentino acosentino Red Hat Antonin Stefanutti  astefanutti  Red Hat Babak Vahdat bvahdat Cyberlogic Consulting GmbH Ben O&amp;rsquo;Day boday Initek Consulting  Bilgin Ibryam bibryam Red Hat Bruce Snyder bsnyder   Charles Moulliard cmoulliard Red Hat  Christian Mueller cmueller Amazon Web Services  Christian Posta ceposta Red Hat Christian Schneider cschneider  Claus Ibsen davsclaus Red Hat  Colm O hEigeartaigh coheigea Talend  David Jencks djencks IBM  Daniel Kulp dkulp Talend  Dmitry Volodin dmvolod Red Hat  Franz Forsthofer forsthofer SAP  Freeman Fang ffang Red Hat Gary Tully gtully Red Hat  Gert Vanthienen gertv    Gregor Zurowski gzurowski Sotheby&amp;rsquo;s  Guillaume Nodet gnodet Red Hat  Hadrian Zbarcea hadrian  Henryk Konsek hekonsek Red Hat Hiram Chirino chirino Red Hat Ioannis Canellos iocanel Red Hat  Jacek Laskowski jlaskowski   James Carman jcarman Savoir Technologies Jean-Baptiste Onofré jbonofre Talend  Jeff Genender jgenender Savoir Technologies Johan Edstrom joed Savoir Technologies  John Poth  Red Hat Jonathan Anstey janstey Red Hat James Netherton Red Hat  James Strachan jstrachan  Luca Burgazzoli lburgazzoli Red Hat  Martin Krasser krasserm Nicky Sandhu nsandhu Onder Sezgin onders Quinn Stevenson quinn Raul Kripalani raulk   Rich Newcomb rnewcomb  Richard Kettelerij rickette Avisi BV Rob Davies rajdavies Roman Kalukiewicz romkal Scott England-Sullivan sully6768 Red Hat  Stan Lewis slewis Red Hat Tadayoshi Sato tsato Red Hat Tomohisa Igarashi igarashitm Red Hat  Tracy Snell tjsnell  Juice Labs Willem Jiang ningjiang Huawei  William Tam wtam Progress Software  Zoran Regvart zregvart Red Hat ## Contributors</description></item><item><title>User Stories</title><link>https://camel.apache.org/community/user-stories/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://camel.apache.org/community/user-stories/</guid><description>This page is intended as a place to collect user stories and feedback on Apache Camel. If you are using or have tried Apache Camel please add an entry or comment; or post to the mailing list.
Company, Product, or Project Description Apache ActiveMQ Uses Camel to add Enterprise Integration Patterns support into the ActiveMQ broker. If you run an out of the box ActiveMQ broker, look in conf/camel.</description></item></channel></rss>